Hello friends, my name is Abhishek Goyal
and welcome to my channel Invest i Shar.
Friends, in our video of ICCI Max Protect,
we had promised all of you
that in the upcoming video we will compare the
plan of IC Max Protect with Cigna's
Life Time Plan and Care Advantage
and will find out which plan
is better. So today in this video we will
compare all the three plans so that you
can choose a better plan for yourself. If you have
come to our channel for the first time, then please
subscribe our channel so that all of you keep getting
such great information. And then
if you like the video, then like and
share it. Let's move ahead and compare all the three plans
in detail. First of all let's talk about
sum insured. If you
see here, then in ICICI you
get a minimum sum insured of Rs 1 crore, whereas
in Cigna it is Rs 50 lakh and
in Care it starts from Rs 25 lakh. If I
talk about the maximum limit, then
unlimited plan is given in ICIC, whereas
in Cigna it is Rs 3 crore and in Care Advantage  A
limit of Rs 6 crore has been given. If I
talk about entries eligibility, then in all the three plans
your minimum is 91 days and if I
talk about maximum entries, then in the first two plans
65 years have been given, whereas in Care
Advantage you have no limit, that is,
you can enter this product whenever you want.
Now if I talk about copayment, then there is
no copayment in the first two plans, whereas
in Care Advantage, if you
enter the product on or after 61 years, then you have to pay a
copayment of Rs 20. Now if I talk about
product variants, then
two variants are given in all the three plans.
In ICICI you have Classic and Premium,
whereas in Cigna and Your Care, the
option of India and Global plan is given. Now let's
talk about room rent and ICU charges,
if you look here, in AAA you
get single private EC room,
in Cigna you get AU room, Accept Suite
and in Care Advantage you are being
provided Actuals, that is,
no room rate.  No limit has been given for
pre and post hospital expenses. If I talk about pre and post hospital expenses, then
in the first two plans you are being given a cover of 60
and 180 days for pre and post hospital
expenses. Whereas
in your Care you are being given a cover power of 30 days and 60 days.
If you
go for the Global Plan of Care Advantage, then
your pre and post becomes 60 and 180 days.
Now let's talk about road ambulance,
then in ICICI you have been given a limit of up to 10000.
Whereas in Cigna and
in your Care Advantage you are being given up to sum shot cover. If I
talk about organ donor, then
in all the three plans you are being given sum shot
coverage. Now if I talk about day care
treatment, then in the first two plans you are being given
up to sum shot coverage. Whereas
in Care Advantage only 541 procedures are being
covered, up to sum insured. Now let's
talk about AYUSH treatment,
in all the three plans you  Up to sum insured
coverage is being given.
If you are undergoing any surgery for obesity reduction, then
you are being given
up to sum insured coverage in the first plan.
Whereas in Cigna there is optional coverage and
you are not being covered for this in Care Advantage. If we
talk about modern treatment, then
you are being given sum insured coverage in almost all the three plans.
However, in ICICI, the company has
given a maximum limit of Rs 1 crore. If we talk about
homeless hospitalization, then in ICICI
you are being given up to sum insured coverage.
Whereas in Cigna, there is a capping of sum insured at Rs 10
and in Care you are being given up to
sum insured coverage. Now let's talk about
no claim bonus, in ICICI you
get no claim bonus at Rs 20 for every claim free
year which increases up to a maximum of 100%. Even
if you have a claim tomorrow,
it does not reduce. Whereas
in Cigna, every year you get  You get a guaranteed bonus on 15
and it is unlimited as long as your policy
is continuous. It will keep increasing continuously.
Whereas in Care Advantage, you get
no claim on 10 which increases up to a maximum of 50
but if you have any
claim tomorrow, it gets reduced in the same proportion.
Now let's talk about
automatic recharge, that is, if tomorrow
your base sub-mesh gets exhausted due to any
claim, then the company
refills your base sub-mesh again.
In the first plan, you
get unlimited restoration. Restoration is also being given to the same person for the same illness.
In Signal Life also, you are being given multiple restorations
but for unrelated illness,
you are being given restoration only once in Care Advantage
for an unrelated
illness. Now let's talk about health
checkup. You are being given health checkup in IIC
but only
in the premium plan whereas in Signal Life time,
your based on your  Sum insured coverage is
provided to you and Care Advantage
is optional for which you have to pay an extra
premium. Now talking about
worldwide coverage, ICICI
offers worldwide coverage but
only in the premium plan.
Cigna Life Time Plan offers
coverage of up to ₹1 crore in case of emergency in the
India plan. If you
opt for the Global plan, you
get worldwide coverage. Care Advantage offers
worldwide coverage only in the Global plan.
Now talking about
value added services, ICICI
offers coverage for this, while Cigna offers
optional coverage. Care Advantage also
offers coverage for this.
Teleconsultation coverage is provided in ICICI and
Care, while Cigna offers optional coverage. You will have to pay an
extra premium for this. Air
ambulance coverage is provided in ICICI again
but
in the premium plan, while Cigna offers optional coverage in
Care. You will have to
pay an extra premium for this. Talking about home care
treatment, ICICI offers coverage for this.  In IIC,
its coverage up to ₹1 lakh is being provided in the premium plan.
In Cigna, it is optional
coverage, whereas in Care, you are
not being given its coverage. Now, let's talk about
non-consumable items,
its coverage is being given in the premium plan of IIC.
In Cigna, you have optional coverage,
whereas in Care Advantage, it is also being
given as optional coverage. Now, let's talk about
second opinion for critical illness,
in IIC, you are being provided
only one time for the same illness, whereas
in Cigna and Care, you are
not being given its coverage. Now, let's talk about some
such benefits which you get in Signal Life Time
Plan, which are not available in other plans. The
first is portability benefit, that is,
if you already have health insurance of some company
and you
port from there to here, then the benefit of no claim bonus is
also available in this product.
For example, you have sum insured of Rs 10 lakh in another company
and you have been insured for the last 5 years.  If you are
running this policy continuously, then as of today,
you have a coverage of ₹50 lakh along with its bonus. So,
if you
take a policy of ₹50 lakh here, then you
get coverage of ₹1 lakh from day one without any waiting
period. Next is premium waiver benefit.
In this, basically the company says that if tomorrow
you get a serious illness or due to
any accident you become permanently disabled, then the
company waives the premium for one year.
Next is loyalty
benefit. If you continue running this policy continuously, then from the
fourth year onwards, the company
gives you a discount of ₹5 on premium till the seventh year and from the 8th year onwards, the company
provides you a discount of ₹10 on premium. Along with this, the company is also providing you
cover for HIV AIDS and
coverage for mental illness. Now let's
talk about the optional benefits which are
given in this product. First of all, let's talk about the
optional benefits which are being
given to you in IC. So the first optional
benefit is  That is room category change.
By default, you
get a single private IS room in this product, but if you
choose this option, you can upgrade to any room.
Second is reduction of
PD waiting period. If you choose this, then
if you have any disease before taking the policy,
like BP, sugar, whose
waiting period is 4 years in this policy, it gets
reduced to 2 years. Now let's
talk about the optional benefits that you
get in Cigna Lifetime. If
you see here, the first optional benefit being
given is critical illness cover.
If you get
any of the critical illnesses listed by the company, then the company
provides you a lump sum benefit.
Next is OPD ride. If you choose this option, then the
company has three to four
OPD packages. If you choose this, then the
company provides you
OPD services in its network hospitals on a cashless basis.
Next is health sheet.
If you choose this, then the company provides non-
consumer  Along with bulk items, it
also provides coverage for durable items.
Next is Health Advance. If you choose this,
you can go to all categories of rooms. The
same person gets registration for the same illness
and also
provides air ambulance coverage up
to Rs. 10 lakh. Next is Health Plus. If you
choose this, the company
provides different types of cash benefits
along with the consultation services.
Next is Women Plus. If you choose this, the
company
provides cancer screening along with
different types of consultation services.
Next is Maternity Coverage. This is a new
optional coverage being offered in this lifetime
plan. If you choose this, the
company provides normal or caesarean
maternity coverage. Along
with that, the company is
also providing surrogacy, infertility and abortion cover. Now let's talk about the
optional benefits
offered in Care Advantage.  If you
look here, first of all the
company is giving you the option to change the room category.
In this product,
Actuals are provided to you by default, that is,
you can take all categories of rooms,
but if you choose this option, then
your room becomes a Single Private EC room,
but at the same time the company
reduces your premium. Next is
PD Waiting Reduction. If you choose this, then
your PD waiting
period which is four years by default
in this product, gets reduced to 2 years.
Next is Smart Select. If you
choose this option, then the company basically
provides a discount of up to 15% on your premium, but at the same
time, whenever you go for any treatment in the future,
you will have to go
to their network listed hospital only.
If you go to any other non-network
hospital for treatment, then
you have to pay a copayment of 15%. Next is
Annual Health Checkup. If you choose this, then all the
insured members
They get free health checkup once in a year
on a cashless basis. Next is Air
Ambulance. If you choose this, then the
company provides air ambulance service of up to ₹ lakh.
Next is Care
Shield. If you choose this, then
you also get coverage for the company's listed non-consumable items. Next is
NCB Super Apart from your normal No
Claim Bonus which the company gives you at 10% per year,
which increases to a maximum of 50%.
If you choose this, then the
company gives an extra 50% No Claim Bonus,
which increases to a maximum of 100%,
but if you get a claim tomorrow, then it gets
reduced in the same proportion.
Next is Co Payment Option. If
you choose this, then the
company reduces your premium by a certain percentage,
but whenever you get a claim in the future,
you will have to pay that much portion
and the rest is given by the health insurance company.
Next is Co Payment Waiver. As
I told you about this product.  If you
enter 61 or later, then you have to make a
mandatory copayment of Rs 20, but if you
choose this option, then your
mandatory copayment of Rs 20 is removed and
you get the full claim. Along with this,
friends, the company has also given the option of
deducted option, daily loan, additional sum assured
for accidental coverage in its policy wording, as well as
unlimited automatic discharge.
But when we try to buy this policy online
or
in the policy market, then
we do not see this option, so
we proceed considering this, these options are
not available right now. Now let's talk about the
waiting period, if you
see here, then in all the three products, you have a
waiting period of two years for
specific illnesses like kidney stone, hemorrhoids,
cataract, beans. Now let's talk about the waiting
period for pre-assisting diseases, that is,
any such disease which you should have before taking the policy,
like BP, sugar. So if you
see here,  In ICICI and Care, you have been given a
waiting period of four years, whereas
in Cigna, you have been given a waiting period of only two years.
If I talk about the
waiting period for biopsy surgery, then
in ICICI and Cigna, you have a waiting period of three years and ten
years, whereas
in Care, its coverage is not being given. If I
talk about worldwide cover, then in IIC, it has a
waiting period of two years, whereas
in Cigna and Care Advantage, you are
not being given any waiting period. Now let's
talk about network hospitals,
ICICI has more than 7500 network
hospitals, Cigna has more than 9000
network hospitals, whereas Care has
more than 10500 network hospitals, so almost
all the big hospitals come in their network list,
so in case of cashless treatment, there will be no
problem, in case of any
emergency, if you get
your treatment done in a non-network hospital, then
if you see here,
in ICICI, you are being given the service of Anywhere Cashless,
where you can pay the company
If it tries to provide information service within 24 hours,
whereas in Cigna and Care, if you do
not get any service related to this, then you will have to
put up your claim on rebus ment basis only.
Now let's talk about premium. Here
I have calculated the premium of Rs
1 crore for a 30-year-old person for all the variants of all the plans.
If you
look here, there are different premiums in all the zones.
However, if you see, in ICC, the
premium is different in all the four zones in Zone A, B, CD.
Whereas in Cigna and Care, there is a difference between Zone A
and Zone B. Whereas the premiums for Zone B, CD are
almost the same.
So friends, in this way we have
covered all the things of all the three products. I hope you
liked the information. We have given the
brochure and policy wording of all the three products
in the description link. If you want, you can go through them separately.
Now let's talk about
which plan should be taken by whom.
Friends, first of all, if
I look at all the three plans, Care Advantage
appears to be a little weak plan due to certain reasons.  There is
no cash bonus reduction in this.
Your automatic recharge is being
given only one time. There is a limit on day care procedures. However, there is
not much difference in the premium. Now let's talk about
which plan should you choose between ICC and Cigna.
If you are looking for coverage up to Rs 50 lakh, then
obviously
you have no choice, you will have to go to Cigna. However,
if you are
looking for coverage up to Rs 1 crore, then Cigna offers
two-three extra benefits
which you do not get in ICSA. For example,
you get maternity coverage and
loyalty benefits. In
case you have a policy running continuously with another company and
port it here, you
get its continuity benefit.
Along with that, the company is providing you the benefit of waiver of
premium.
Now let's talk about what is
available to you in ICC. Here you are being
given any-where cashless facility.
Along with this, you  International coverage
is offered at a reasonable premium. So, it's up to you to decide
your requirements. If
you're looking for an India plan with maternity coverage and higher summation,
go with the
Cigna plan. If you're looking for international
coverage with higher summation, then you
can go with the ICICI plan. But let me
tell you one more thing: ICICI
also offers zone-wise capping.
That means, if you're in Zone C and then get
treatment in Zone A,
you'll have to pay there.
Cigna doesn't offer this. So, this is a
slight disadvantage compared to Cigna
's lifetime plan. I hope you
liked our small comparison and analysis. We deal with products from all major health
insurance companies
and
provide product sales and services all over India. So, if you're interested in joining us for
health or life insurance,
you can contact us at the number below.
Or, if you have any
minor health-related queries, you can contact us at the number below.  So you
can ask us in the comment box below,
we will try to answer your questions.
If you like the video then like,
share and subscribe. Thank you.